THEME SONG: In the not too
distant future, next Sunday AD,
there was a guy named Joel, not
too different from you or me.
He worked at Gizmonic
Institute, just another face
in a red jumpsuit.
He did a good job
cleaning up the place.
But his bosses didn't like him
so they shot him into space.
We'll send him cheesy movies,
the worst we can find.
La-la-la.
He'll have to sit
and watch them all.
And we'll monitor his mind.
La-la-la.
Now, keep in mind Joel can't
control where the movies being
or end.
La-la-la.
Because he used
those special parts
to make his robot friends.
Robot Roll Call.
All right, let's go!
Cambot.
Pan Left!
Gypsy!
Hi, girl!
Tom Servo.
What a cool guy!
Crow!
He's a wisecracker.
If you're wondering how
he eats and breathes,
and other science facts.
La-la-la.
Then repeat to yourself,
it's just a show.
I should really just relax for
Mystery Science Theater 3000!
-Hey, hey, Tiny.
Look at me when I'm
talking to you, all right.
-I'm looking.
-Now, like I was saying,
I think we can scout out
what the Uberlords have planned
for this week's movie, thanks
to the game film supplied
courtesy of Cambot over there.
[CHATTERING]
-All right.
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
Hey.
Hey, Superdestroyer.
Hey, buddy.
-Huh?
-I'll wait-- wait for it, OK?
I'll say, beat 'em.
And then you say, beat
'em, beat 'em, beat 'em.
OK?
-Duh, OK, coach.
-All right.
Now like I was saying, we
can have a pretty good idea
what their psychological
offense is going to be.
-Uh-huh.
-Remember last week they sent
us that cheese-eater of a biker
film, "Wild Rebel," a definite
win for our team, hey?
[CHEERING]
-All right.
But-- hey, hey.
But the week before
that, at our homecoming,
they sent us
"Rocket Attack USA."
[GRUMBLING]
FEMALE VOICE (ON PA):
Commercial sign in 15 seconds.
-Oh.
-Oh is right.
It was a standard-issue
bloodletting
of our pop and
folk sensibilities.
We almost lost our
star setter Gypsy.
[CHATTERING]
-Oh, I love you guys.
FEMALE VOICE (ON
PA): Commercial sign
in five, four, three, two, one.
-Beat 'em, beat 'em, beat 'em.
FEMALE VOICE (ON
PA): Commercial sign.
[CHANTING]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
-No, Crow.
You can't use a man-to-man
defense on these type of films.
It's strictly got to be zone.
How you going to pick up
the extra man on the give
and go and not end up
in the trophy case?
-Hey, coach.
If I really sky under
the boards tonight,
can I have some arms
that actually work?
-Listen, I-- I don't have time.
Uh, the mad scientists
are calling.
Why don't you talk to
the trainer or something?
-But Joel, you're our trainer.
-Yeah.
-Just get out there, you
bunch of panty waists.
Beat 'em.
Come on.
-Beat 'em, beat 'em, beat 'em.
Ah, good afternoon, bumpiss.
It's a nice day for a
bloodletting, wouldn't you say?
Well, in regards
to today's movie,
I'm just going to
say rock climbing.
-Rock climbing?
-Yes, rock climbing.
But before our
sweet-but-not-too-spicy delve
into terror, spotlight invention
exchange on young Frank.
Oh, Frank?
-Thanks, boss.
You know, People love to use
stationary exercise treadmills
for their daily
exercise routine.
But when it gets nice
outside, what do we do?
Dr. Forrester?
-Uh, we go to the lake, Frank?
-Exactly.
Oh, nice camera work
thee, Jerry and Sylvia.
We go to the lake.
We-- back me up on
this one, people.
We go to the lake.
So now when it's
nice out and you
want to go outside
and exercise, you
can take your stationary
exercise treadmill with you,
like this.
What do you think, boss?
-Oh, couldn't you
just walk, Frank?
-I've also, uh, taken this
prototype for a stairs machine.
This is really good.
You go from one
landing to the next
as you exercise on the stairs.
It's really quite unbelievable.
It's really something else.
-Uh, nice-- nice work, you two.
As for you, you big
dumb kid, you just
invented the staircase.
-Thank you.
And hear me out on this one.
What I've done is I've
invented a rowing machine.
And what I've done is I've
put a rowboat underneath it,
so you can actually go out
into the lake as you exercise.
I mean, because we do that.
-Would you give me those?
-We do that.
We go to the--
-Crazy fool.
[WHEEZING] Rock climbing.
Rock climbing.
-Oh, yes.
-Rock climbing, Jerry.
-Rock climbing.
-Rock climbing, Sylvia.
-In all the excitement,
I forgot rock climbing.
-Rock climbing.
-Well, before we
get to our film,
which is a steamy experiment
into the bowels of--
-Clay, may I?
-You may.
-Thank you very much.
It's called "Lost Continent."
and I'm very excited about it,
because it is Cesar Romero,
Hugh Beaumont a giant lizard,
the guy from "The Danny
Thomas Show," and oh,
did I mention rock climbing?
Rock climbing, guys.
Rock climbing.
-As for you, Joel, I'm sorry.
We don't have time for
your invention this week.
Hate to spoil your soup.
Paste them, Frank.
-You are all going
to die. [LAUGHS]
[BUZZING]
-I absolutely refuse to go into
the theater against my will.
That's absolutely it.
Ow!
Ow, I got movie starting
against my will!
-Beat 'em, beat 'em, beat
'em, beat 'em, beat 'em.
-Those guys didn't let me
do my invention exchange.
-The incredible Mr. Lippert.
-Hey, lady face.
-Lippert the Lion.
Hardy har har.
-"Lost Continent"?
I lost my keys once,
but that's ridiculous.
[LAUGHTER]
-Hey, he must have
had a good agent.
His stones are 10 feet tall.
-Chick, Chick Chandler.
Hey, look, Acquanetta.
Snot is running down her nose.
-Hugh Beaumont and Murray
Alper as the beaver?
Nyuk, nyuk, nyuk.
-Martin Landau's brother.
Forever young's brother.
Oh, look.
Dunlap, the tire magnate.
-Oh, Jack Green [CLEARS
THROAT] Phlegm guy.
-He's in charge of phlegm.
-Lee Press-on-wood.
-And all the
insignificant people.
-Do not remove this tag
under penalty of law!
-Tom Productions?
-Produced by Sigmund Neufeld.
And directed by his
brother, Samuel Newfield.
They were in separate lines
on Ellis Island, you see.
-Hey, there's Carlos Castaneda,
looking for Don Juan.
-Oh, no!
-No.
-No!
Haven't we seen this before?
-Yup.
Oh, White Sands.
Isn't that where they get
all that stuff for the hotel
ashtrays?
-Oh, look, it's a V2.
-Aw, I could have had a V8.
-Aw, seen it.
-Yup.
-Quit looking over his shoulder.
He can't work that way.
-We are on our way!
-He's playing pong solitaire.
[GIGGLE]
-So, that's what war
does at the office.
-They're really into it.
-I'm into it, too.
I don't mind telling you.
-Don't forget me.
-What's it rate of
climb, sergeant?
-(GERMAN ACCENT) 2,000
feet, mein fuhrer.
-Phillips, give me a reading
on altitude and distance.
-Phillips, give
me a screwdriver.
-I'll have a Rum and Tab.
-Sloe Gin Fizz for me.
-1,000 miles an hour.
It's 900 miles since
time of launching.
We'll be losing it in
a couple of minutes.
-I know that.
-She's right on course.
-Hello, Nobel.
-Jane, stop this crazy thing.
Jane.
-Dr. Rostov, it's as if this
atomic-powered engine of yours
is going to outmode
jet propulsion.
-Oh, quit kissing up.
-It's out of range, sir.
-Hm.
-Desert Station, calling
Top of the World.
-Top of the world, Ma!
-Stop this crazy thing!
-It all started at a
little 500-watt radio
station in Fresno, California.
-Look.
That could change the
game of lacrosse forever.
-Large-scale pong.
-Hello, Desert Station, pip
moving in on Top of the World.
-Ma!
MAN (ON RADIO):
Altitude, 23 miles.
Speed, 1800 miles an hour.
-Attitude, not too good.
MAN (ON RADIO): On
course as charted.
She's practically over our heads
right now, heading out to sea.
-Oh, it's the wackiest
ship in the army.
-There's never been an
escape from [INAUDIBLE].
Oh, god.
-Now, this is a visual
representation of a theremin.
-Contact Desert Station--
-Contact this.
MAN (ON RADIO): Captain
to Desert Station.
Captain to Desert Station.
Come in, Desert Station.
Over.
-Hold me.
-Hey, it's droopy.
-(GERMAN ACCENT) Rocket
working very good.
MAN (ON RADIO): We're
1,000 miles above sea.
-I wonder what the
boys are up to.
-Altitude, 38 miles.
-I just discovered I
look like Robert Ryan.
-Speed, 2000 miles an hour.
Rocket approaching
point return back.
-Hey, it's Dino.
What a ding-a-ling.
Hey, Jerry, there's something
wrong with the stock footage
simulator.
-[INAUDIBLE]
-Hello, Neptune.
We are waiting.
Come in.
-This is Neptune,
God of the Sea.
-You get me, Neptune?
You get me?
This is Desert Station.
We are waiting.
Anything wrong?
-No, just everything.
Just dump on me.
-Oh, what's the matter?
-Eh, Jerry, were you
messing with this?
-Oh, that cuts it, Dean.
Dean.
-Desert Station, we
can't reverse the rocket.
It's out of control.
It won't turn back.
The rocket isn't turning back.
-Goodbye, Nobel.
-It's 100 miles past us.
120, 50, 75.
-Uh-oh.
-200--
-No, not 200!
No!
-Desert Station calling Neptune.
MAN (ON RADIO):
Yes, Desert Station.
-Give me that.
-This is Dr. Michael Rostov.
Are you sure your
reading is correct?
Are you sure you
haven't miscalculated?
-Oh yeah, I'm the jerk.
It couldn't be
your crappy rocket.
-Came in right on schedule,
on its exact course.
-Where is it now?
-It's getting below the horizon.
-Hm.
Bye.
-Hurts, doesn't it?
-Ouch.
-Neptune still standing
by, Desert Station.
What orders?
-Have them keep a clear channel.
-Yes, sir.
-Well, I better tell
June to hold supper.
-I don't like this.
-Stand by.
You can all clear.
-Roger.
Neptune standing by.
Over.
-Hold me.
-Dr. Briggs, traveling
three more hours
at its present rate of speed,
same fixed course, where would
you say it would crash?
-Well, here's us.
-Somewhere within this radius.
-Not good, is it?
-No, it's not good.
-If we can ever
recover it, we'll
find why it didn't come back.
-Oh, he's just
grasping at straws now.
-Yeah.
-You know what this test means.
-Does this mean
we can kill stuff?
-Right now it's a failure.
-Oh, so we're the jerks now.
-We've always managed to
be first in the long race
against time.
We proved that
with the atom bomb.
-My head's a plaster
cast of Robert Mitchell.
-Or if someone else should
recover it before we do--
-Why's he looking at me?
I didn't do anything.
Get away!
-It isn't the money, we spent,
it's the time out of the lives
of men like--
-Shame, shame, shame.
- --Rostov and
Phillips and Briggs.
-Wall-E, Mopey, Whitey,
the Beave, Eddie.
-Those hours represent
a large portion
of our nation's security.
-And I'm talking to you, Bob.
-If we don't get that rocket
back, we may never survive.
You know just how
much security we lost.
-Look, I feel bad enough, OK?
-I'll get an OK
for a search party.
-And I don't want to
hear I don't know.
-Jerk.
-Who died and made him Droopy?
-I don't know.
- --line to the White House.
-Oh, the White House.
We're all impressed.
-Adam and Eve on a
raft and a-- huh?
-Ah, toasty fire.
-Another [INAUDIBLE]?
-No, thanks.
Coffee's bad for
my sense of humor.
-It makes me slur my words.
-With you, I'll have to
stay on my good behavior.
-Mrs. Roosevelt's looking fine.
-Mm-hm.
-Not at all.
That's what it's there
for, Major Nolan.
-Joe's the name, remember?
-Tail gunner Joe.
-Don't let the
rank frighten you.
-Habit, I guess.
-I guess.
You don't seem to be running
out of inhibitions either.
-Drink your drink, Joe.
-Yes, Mommy.
-Marla, I--
-Tell me more about your
being a flight instructor.
The boys you trained to fly--
what are they like today?
-Oh, they're dead.
[CLEARS THROAT] Sorry.
-Well, they're--
-No more hot-rod jockey pod.
There's no more flying by
the seat of their pants.
These boys think.
The day of the prop-on
planes is over.
-These boys flying today
have to know their engineers.
-Just keep talking, dickweed.
-They're after the same kind
of brainpower that MIT is,
or Carnegie Tech, or--
-Hey.
-Hey, wait a minute.
You had me doing this
same show the other night.
-I just wanted to see if
you had any new material.
-It was-- let me see.
You were taking me up to
the door to say goodnight.
-You tried to use me as a key.
-Oh, I remember.
You wanted to come
inside and show me
how you simulated
landings at 10,000.
-Oh, I was drunk, wasn't I?
-Oh, sure.
What's the matter with me?
That was Tuesday
night I saw you.
-Mm, no.
-Wednesday.
-Oh, then your name's
not Betty, is it?
-Yeah, sure.
Of course.
Wednesday.
-Doh.
-Crash landings?
-Nope.
-Parachute jumps?
-Clown suits?
-Yeah.
-Take-offs?
-I was tired that night, Joe.
You left me at the front door.
-Aw.
-Oh, please don't get up.
I'll change the record.
-Oh, jeez.
I really dropped the ball.
Gotta stay in control.
I'm still a champ.
I can do it.
-Hm, hey look. "The Dead," "Mel
Torme," and here's one of mine.
Huh?
[MUSIC PLAYING]
-He is neat.
Really nice caboose.
-Mm.
Oh, Marcel Marceau's album.
-Dinner was magnificent.
-Oh, we did eat
dinner, didn't we?
-Let's give the music
a break, shall we?
-Oh, would you give us a break?
-Oh, yeah.
- --worry about my figure.
A woman appreciates
such thoughtfulness.
-I'll soon have you down
to fighting weight, honey.
-What a shame.
-I lead.
Give to Cesar what is Cesar's.
-Fly a plane as
well as you dance?
-I manage.
Those simulated landings--
[SLURPING]
-Oh, you taste like Bud Abbott.
-Get the clown suit.
-Well, it certainly
took you a long time
getting around to that, Major.
-It will never happen again.
[DOOR BUZZING]
-Oh, it's like an
Operation game.
Touche her there and she buzzes.
-Remove tongue from tonsils.
-There's the door.
-I don't hear anything.
-Maybe you better answer it.
-It's my electric truss.
-Great to see she's
got a nice back, ay?
-Excuse me, Major.
Are you wearing your jimmy hat?
-Pardon me, ma'am.
But is Major Nolan here?
-Oh, is that who I am?
-Hi.
-What is it, Sergeant?
-My neck, sir.
It's fused to my spine.
Ow, ow, ow.
-Orders for you to report
back to the base at once, sir.
They'll have a plane warming
up for you at the flight line.
-I was just warming up myself.
-At once?
-At once, sir.
-All right, Sergeant.
-Oh, well.
-Come back soon, Joe.
-And, uh, bring your jimmy hat.
-I'd like to finish our--
[THROATS CLEARING]
- --discussion about
simulated landings.
[WHISTLING]
-What time is it, Sergeant?
-2:30, sir.
-Hold back on the stick.
-Well, it's a whole lot
better than near 3:00.
-Mm, mwah!
-She's not bad, sir, if you
don't mind me saying it.
-I don't mean to sound personal,
Sergeant, but how did you--
-Just following orders, Major.
If I hadn't have come across
this at your quarters, I, uh,
might not have found you
for another 30 minutes.
-Uh, he's pretty old for
a sergeant, isn't he?
-He must have
punched an officer.
-Very careless of you, sir.
-Give me that.
-These are all guys!
-If you don't mind my
saying so, sir, you're
an awfully tough man to follow.
-She's hot.
-Why I oughta-- knucklehead.
-I'll be right back.
[MONKEY NOISES]
-What was that guy's name again?
I remember.
-Uh, the guy who was on
"The Danny Thomas Show."
-Oh, that's his name.
-I don't want any
more complaints
out of you, sweetheart.
Willie gave you all new parts.
Now use 'em.
And you, my blood you got.
Half the night I spent over you.
What happens?
Wrong size.
Now you got a new one that fits.
Use it.
Be relaxed and satisfied.
-Sergeant Tatlow.
-Hey, it does talk.
-The CO wants you.
-Oh, it's him.
-What, and leave us sitting
here practically naked?
-Well, put your pants
on and get going.
- --hot and cold baths
in a straight jacket,
that's your business.
Mine is to take you to the CO.
You coming?
-Orders, heh.
It's all they know.
They get 'em, they give 'em.
You get 'em, you're stuck.
And does your draft board care?
Eh.
-Eh.
-Come on.
-Mwah.
I love this old suit.
Ah.
-Everybody talks to inanimate
objects in this movie.
Pretty strange.
-Now, don't misunderstand me.
I don't want to make
you feel terrible.
But I always said I've
never die in a plane.
-But I've changed my mind.
-Let me see.
Aw.
-Mother.
-She got married last month.
-That makes me legitimate now.
-Ah, my brother Russell.
He made the pep squad.
-I'll keep them flying, Jackie.
Follow my leave.
I'll tell you all about
it when I get back.
-[LAUGHS] Here we go.
Huh?
Oh.
-Lieutenant Wilson?
-Where?
-One L or two?
-Uh, five!
-Lieutenant Daniel Wilson.
-Got your library card, sir.
-CO wants you right away.
-Uh-oh.
-Dame said she voted last year.
-What?
-Maybe she lied.
I can't understand it.
-Woosh.
I think that's over our heads.
-As I was telling
that other guy,
I never wanted to
die in a plane.
But now I'm very
excited about it.
-All right, give me
another Rum and Diet.
Then we auger it in, Phil.
-Dad, Dad, can we stop?
I gotta go to the bathroom.
-Hey, come on.
-We're gonna get there.
Are we there yet?
Can we stop?
-I lost out on a little
contentment and peace myself.
-What?
-So why pick on me?
-Because I missed your
ugly face, Danny boy.
I got lonesome.
-Come on.
-Because you were so pleasant
and uncomplaining those two
delightful years we spent living
in that romantic South Pacific
jungle together.
-Jeez, everything's a
speech with these guys.
-We got to crash
on an island that's
loaded with
guerrilla resistance.
-You made it sound so
good, I'm taking us in.
And
-Then in two seconds, you're
a South Pacific commando.
What a picnic.
-You got liberated.
-Yeah, I got liberated.
-So did she.
Boom.
-Look where it got me.
-Liberation, it's
a wonderful thing.
-Hm?
-There's strength to it.
-Oh, it must be a
Northwestern flight.
Huh?
-Hm?
-Uh, yeah.
-How about some coffee?
-No thanks.
I already had mine.
[LAUGHS] I love that.
-If it's not one
thing, it's another.
-Coming right up, sir.
-Eh, I gotta-- oh, ah.
Forget that rest stop.
I'm fine now.
-Meanwhile over Ames, Iowa--
-That guys' kind of a
chunky steward, isn't he?
-Mm.
-Yeah, pardon me, Doc.
I brought some coffee.
-Oh, uh, I-- I wasn't
doing anything. [LAUGHS]
-Smells good.
-It's just me, oof.
-Let me tell you, Doc.
Everything about this
doll smells good.
Just look at the fuselage.
Really stacked, eh?
-Oh, you've been alone too
long, haven't you, Sergeant?
-Listen to her sing.
I tell you, she's a dream, Doc.
My baby.
-If she can only cook.
-Hey, you're talking
about the woman he loves.
-Aw, Doc, hey, I
can see you haven't
had much experience with things.
You know, the first
thing you got to know
is never-- never
spoil their makeup.
-Ah, uh-huh. [LAUGH]
You're really
bucking for that
Section Eight, pal.
-I'm the wrong guy to ask, Doc.
You know, looking
out from high places
makes little black spots do
a ballet in front of my eyes.
-(RUSSIAN ACCENT) I can
prove these guys don't exist.
-Thank you, Mick.
-Remind me to kill you later.
-Uh, got some
coffee for you, Doc.
-Coffee?
-Yeah, it's a beverage.
-Oh, yes, thanks.
Oh, it's just what I
need about this time.
-Oh, definitely.
-Uh, and suicide
has a U in it, sir.
-You get out of here.
Doh.
-Doo-doo-do.
Huh?
[MONKEY NOISES]
-Uh, genocide has
a C in it, sir.
-(GERMAN ACCENT) Would
you get out of here?
-Oh.
Heh.
I don't know about you,
Doc, but these long trips
always get me a little sleepy.
Figured a little coffee might
keep us all awake, Yeah.
-(GERMAN ACCENT) I don't sleep.
Get away from me,
little monkey boy.
-Man, don't say hi.
Jeepers.
-(GERMAN ACCENT)
We'll hollow you out
and use you as a sleeping bag?
-You ever fly one
of these before?
-Nope.
-Neither have I.
-OK.
-OK, let's see here.
Who had the Manhattan, and
who had 15 Rum and Diet Cokes?
Good thing we
stocked up at Fargo.
-Oh, what characters.
You're as bad as plying
a bunch of congressmen
to visit the war front.
-Really, how you talk.
This is a posh assignment.
-What a fem.
-We're hauling VIPs,
distinguished scientists.
-Ha, ha, hoo.
-Sergeant, you should have
brewed them some liquid
hydrogen served
with smashed atoms--
-Somebody's hurting.
-Mm-hm.
-Yeah.
Yeah, I'll serve 'em.
One joke was taking
pictures through a window.
Another one looks like he's
writing a letter to Einstein.
That Rostov guy is
playing games with a map.
But what do we do?
Go chasing after a rocket.
-That's a naughty
word, Sergeant.
Top secret.
Hey, take over.
-Me?
I'm going a Sergeant.
-I'm going to play
Boy Scout back there,
let you two
aggravate each other.
-Let's get out of here.
-Ah.
-Eh.
Pick me.
[GRUMBLING]
-Hey, did you ever fly
one of these things?
-Ulcers, he says.
My ulcers never had us a good
[INAUDIBLE] with me this trip.
-Turns off the hose,
climbs down to the ladder,
turns to the clown, and says,
what, and quit show business?
[LAUGHS]
-Tom, I'd really love
to laugh at that.
But I'm the one
who told it to you.
Essentially, I programmed
it into your memory.
Remember?
-Oh, yeah.
-Oh, here's one you'll like.
You'll want to get this.
You'll like this.
OK.
There's these four monks,
an albino squirrel,
and a shoe factory.
OK.
-Wait, there's a ship
coming into range.
-OK, you can tell you
joke when I'm done.
-Uh, no.
No, it's no joke.
-But no-- or your anecdote,
or whatever you got.
-But anyway there's
these four monks.
And they work on a
construction crew.
This is neat.
They work on a construction
crew at the monastery.
OK And they just
get done working--
-Joel, Joel, Joel.
- on some of the
stations of the cross.
-Joel, Joel, Joel.
-And they see this
albino squirrel,
who carries it really well.
And--
-Joel, Joel.
-Oh, would you cut that out?
-Well, hey.
Jeez, what a grouch.
It's the only way I
could get your attention.
-Hey, there's a ship
coming into range.
-[SIGH]
-Willikers, he's right.
Cambot, give me Rocket
Number Nine, pronto.
[DOORBELL]
-Hello, boys.
-Hugh Beaumont.
-Oh, come on.
Call me dad.
-Gee, sir.
I mean, Dad.
What are you doing here?
-Well, you see boys.
I'm one of the Four
Horsemen of the Apocalypse.
And, uh, I come bearing a
message of unholy death.
-Huh?
-That's right.
I'm really going to
give you the business.
Destroy you, your world,
and all that you know.
But first, a stern talking to.
You know, you boys shouldn't
be so hard on that movie.
A lot of people worked
quite hard to bring
that movie to you.
-Gee, I guess we shouldn't be
so quick to judge others then,
huh?
-That's right, Crow.
-(WHISPERING) He bought it.
What a jerk.
-Well, I'm glad we learned
a little lesson then.
Well, it's time to die.
-Gee, sir.
I mean, Dad.
Why must you kill
all life and matter?
-Yeah, can't you give
us another chance?
-Oh, please, Dad.
Don't kill us take our souls
to the afterworld and stuff.
-Boys, I-- I think I
owe you an apology.
I guess your mother
and I got so wrapped up
in this apocalypse
thing I didn't
have time to think how you felt.
-Well, then you're not
going to destroy us?
-Oh, I don't see how I could.
Well, I've got to get going.
I've got to catch up to
Fred MacMurray and the boys.
They're about to destroy Earth.
Drink your milk.
-What a sweet guy.
-Yeah.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
-Once so, we invade Poland.
-Hey, I can see my
house from here.
-Yeah.
You ever fly one
of these things?
-No.
-Me neither.
-Looks like this is it.
-Oh, Stucky's.
-We're now approaching
rocket's point of departure
where Neptune Radar
Unit lost contact.
-Put your shoes on, kids.
We're circling grandma's.
-I wish my life had
meaning. [MONKEY NOISE]
-I can't believe they charge
$3.50 for those things.
-From now on, keep
your eyes peeled.
-Ouch.
-The rocket hit the ocean.
You'll see a dye marker
covering the spot.
I'm going upstairs
so we can get a look.
-Uh, Bob.
This is a plane.
There is no upstairs.
-Meanwhile, over
Bowling Green Tennessee.
-Hey, you ever fly
one of these things?
-Nope.
-Neither have I.
-Hey, I can see my
house from here.
-We're now in the zone where
rocket ran out of fuel.
-This is the pilot.
Anybody back there ever
flown one of these.
-(GERMAN ACCENT) I
know it's my fault.
-I miss the beaver.
-Hey, I can see my
house from here.
-Have you--
-Oh, don't even ask.
-You sure?
-Yeah.
-OK.
-Hm.
-Dead end.
Dead end.
-(SINGING) Dead end,
dead end, dead end,
dead end. [LAUGHS] Sorry.
-Huh?
-What?
-Hm.
-River.
-Island to your left.
I'm swinging over it
so you can take a look.
-Hm.
-His left.
-I can see his scalp from here.
-Cool.
[TRILLING MUSIC]
-Hm?
-Hey.
My-- my watch has
never done that before.
It's trilling.
-Hm.
This place is
crawling with Goldak.
-Rostov, Briggs.
-Rico Youngblood.
-The Geiger's jumping
all over the place.
-Meanwhile, over
Three Mile Island.
-Whoa, I can see our
careers from here.
-Right hand red.
-Oh, you ever crashed
one of these before?
-Uh, I'll get coffee.
-I was kidding about
that death pact, Hal.
Come on.
-Hey, what happened?
-We're losing altitude fast.
-Hey, don't get
technical with me.
-All the magnetic
controls are conked out.
The electrical system's shot.
Whole panel is dead, Joe.
As dead as we'll be if you don't
ditch this baby and bail out.
-No, we'll be deader.
- --and take care of the others.
I'm going to try to
make that island.
-Yeah, I'll go get coffee.
-The captain has put
on No Smoking sign.
Your seat back doubles
as a flotation device.
-You look good.
And you Adolf--
you look fabulous.
-Help me!
-You ever dive one
of these things?
-We blew it, Phil.
Damn fly.
[MONKEY NOISES]
-I'm only lending
[INAUDIBLE], Major.
Bring it back to
me in one piece.
-Can't you tell?
I want to die with you.
-Be kind.
Be gentle with her.
She won't double cross you.
Easy, Major.
-Oh, that looks
like a good place.
-Oh, where's George
Kennedy when you need him?
-You ever crash one
of these things?
-[CLEARS_THROAT]
-Thank you for flying Northwest.
-Hey, we landed on a witch.
Maybe the film will be
in color from this point.
-All right, you kids.
Quit horsing around back there.
-Well, it's time to let
you play in-flight Twister.
-Woo-hoo.
-It smells like a
wrestling match.
-Yo.
-Get the first aid kit.
Briggs is bleeding.
-You did a beautiful job, Major.
-I didn't think we had a chance.
-Let's form a soccer
team and eat each other.
-This will hurt for a minute.
-Yeah, that's what I
always tell my kids.
-Ow, ow.
-What went wrong?
-Maybe there was hand soap
in the hydraulic fluid.
Magnetic instruments,
the radio, everything--
they just stopped cold.
-That's strange.
-I usually have a line here.
-Just before we
crashed, the Geiger
registered intense
radio activity.
-Hm.
-Oh.
-Huh?
-What do you make of that?
-[INAUDIBLE].
Oh.
-We're over something hot.
Other than that, your
guess is as good as mine.
-Oh, whoa!
-Get the Geiger.
Whoa!
-Lot of Goldak reading here.
Oh, thank goodness.
-It sounds like an
old Duran Duran tape.
-Oh, "Hungry Like the Wolf?"
-Yeah, you got it.
-This is an old movie.
-Oh, no Goldak here.
-I can see you're really
upset about this, Dave.
-But there's nothing.
-Hey, my watch is going.
It stopped before,
but now it's going.
-Great.
I'll alert the media.
-Let's go out and take a look
at this South Sea paradise.
-You'll be all right, Briggs.
-Yeah, what a joker.
-Ah, just put that anywhere.
-Oh, what a day.
-Yeah, you left the
morning paper here.
-Beautiful.
-What a place.
-Good morning.
-Morning.
-Seems rather peaceful.
-Talked to some of our guys
who crashed in New Guinea
during the war.
-Whoa.
I'm sorry I brought it up.
-There may be a park, but I'm
not going to depend on it.
-Hey, maybe we oughta try to
get the radio working, huh?
Let somebody know where we are?
-Hey, maybe it's time to
take that parachute off.
- --until we find the rocket.
-Oh, that's just fine.
Head hunters, cannibals.
-Break out the guns
and ammunition.
-It's time for a celebration!
-Yee-haw.
-Better check all
your equipment.
Take only the essential things.
-Like Vitalis.
-Looks like we might be
camping out for a while.
-Night falls quickly
in the jungle.
-Whoa.
-But morning comes just as soon.
-Guys, this kind of reminds
me of a movie I once saw,
about two guys who crashed
in a jungle on the--
-I wish we could have
a charbroiled hamburger
sandwich and some french fried.
Potatoes.
-Oh, that's what
I'm talking about.
-Heh, heh.
Yeah!
-Oops, there goes another
rubber tree plant.
-Thanks, Frank.
-Hey, are they
walking in a circle?
-Ah.
-Hey, I hope
there's a gift shop.
-What do you think?
-Who knows?
Maybe we're being
set up for pigeons.
-And you're the mother-loving
pigeon of them all.
[COOING]
-Well, just remember
the rule, everybody.
If you don't understand
it, shoot it.
-Look for a woman named Wanama.
-Gilligan?
-Mary Anne?
-Torch the village.
Let's do the whole village, man.
Let's do it!
-It's a Gauguin still life!
Shoot it!
-Hey.
Beaver, June, what
are you doing here?
-This ain't gonna
be such a bad leave.
-It's perfect.
Boy, not bad.
-[CLEARS_THROAT] Scuze me.
You know how to get back to
the interstate from here?
-All right.
Jim, Mack, Joe, Fred, Michael.
-Too bad we don't
know their language.
-Yeah, she might
be able to help us.
-I know a couple of
Melanesian dialects.
I'll try them out on her.
-Who are you?
-Whoa!
Don't do that.
-You know English.
-From missionary school.
Island over there,
where my people go.
-It's called Harvard.
-You're people left?
-Why?
-Fire bird fly over village.
Send out flame and smoke.
-The rocket.
It must be the rocket!
-Duh.
-Earth tremble.
People frightened.
Leave in boats.
-Oh, big day for you, huh?
-This fire bird--
where did it land?
-On sacred mountain,
home of gods.
Chief say spirit angry at
bird, make earth tremble.
-Run out of Chronos.
-Why didn't you leave
with the rest of them.
-Rocks fall down.
-Rock stupid.
-My father hurt.
-Aw.
-Brother and I
stay until he die.
-Aw.
-But who are you?
-I'm Cesar Romero,
international Latin star.
-Take away its evil.
-They can do that?
-Whoa, Saboo speaks.
-If you could take us
to where it landed.
-No, no.
-(SINGING) No no, no, no, no no.
-If you show us where
this fire bird came down,
we can break its spell.
It will never fly again.
-And then we'll give you
some glass beads and stuff.
-You sure?
-Your people can come
home, live in peace again.
-I show way to sacred mountain.
But it is taboo.
You will not come back.
-All right.
Follow me, boys.
Oh, uh.
Mm-hm.
[PURRING]
-Oh, yeah.
Oh, swing to the right.
Whoa-ho.
Look out.
-Ah.
-There's sacred
mountain, home of gods.
-Did you make that out
of mashed potatoes?
-Couldn't land on
a nice, soft beach.
Got to pick the
top of a mountain.
-Well, there's nothing yet.
Any radioactivity would
be shielded from us
by the mountain.
-Yeah, it's FM.
-Aren't you coming with us?
-No.
-Me no got leaf sarong.
-Sacred mountain taboo.
No one ever come back
from home of gods.
-Besides you guys, not
see woman in long time.
-That's the first dame I
ever saw run out on you, Joe.
Must be losing your touch.
-Huh.
Funny, jerk.
-I like these guys.
We'll be right back.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
-Uh, what happened
to their torsos?
-Well, fellas,
looks like we came
upon a sacred burial ground.
What say we defile it?
-Looks like a dumping ground.
-Hey, did you ever walk
through one of these before?
-Will you let that die, please?
-Sorry.
-Hm.
Neat.
-Well, looks like
we start climbing.
-Duh.
It seems we have no alternative.
-And one thing, nobody
can say we're not
getting plenty of
exercise on this trip.
-Who needs it?
-Uh, did everybody
get a line now?
-Hey, you can't
even see the top.
-You get dizzy up
there, Sergeant,
and you want to bail out, you've
always got your parachute.
-Yeah, what happens
if it's dark?
-You won't get lost.
You light matches
on the way down.
-Uh, is everybody done
heaping shame on me?
-Phew.
I got to follow that?
Whoa, ugh.
-Get me.
I'm almost out of the frame.
-Look at that.
They've got their wing-tipped
climbing oxfords on there.
-Hm.
-Climb every mountain
till you find your dream.
I don't think so.
-You ever seen "Eiger
Sanction?" [LAUGHS]
-Help me.
-Hey, Joel.
What's that on his belt?
-Oh, that's his, uh, femur bone.
-Oh.
Carries a spare?
-Mm-hm.
[HUMMING]
-Boo!
-Oh!
You got me.
-Whew.
[SHOUTING]
-Just kidding.
-Take my hand.
-Love on the rocks.
-Oh, big surprise.
-Uh, hey, could you turn down
your Aaron Copland watch,
please?
-Joel, why are we
watching this dull
mountain-climbing sequence?
-Well, because it's there.
-Aw.
-Rock climbing, Joel.
-Boo!
-Ah!
-Whoa!
Oh, don't do that.
-Well, there's a little
trick I learned, uh,
either from Will Rogers
or Bob Mapplethorpe.
I can't remember who.
-Wow.
Roping a wild rock
isn't easy to do.
-Yee-hoo.
-(RUSSIAN ACCENT) How fortunate.
This will simplify everything.
-I'm going to climb up
and into Lincoln's nose.
-Remember, Robin, both
hand on the Batrope.
-Don't look at my pant leg.
-Uh, some of these maneuvers
are just for me, folks.
-Please.
[GROANING]
-Let him go.
-Heh, cute.
-I'm here, Steve.
I got you.
-No one will be admitted during
the breathtaking climbing
scene.
-Rock climbing, Crow.
-Rock climbing.
-Rock climbing, Joel-- Crow.
-It's secure up
heeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeere.
-Uh, yuck.
There's Vitalis
all over this rope.
Cesar.
-Well, it looks like
I'm the first man-- oh.
-Heh, heh, oh.
-Almost caught him.
-Oh, let me tell you, working
the Catskills is tough.
Oh.
-Dope on a rope.
-Doh.
-For god's sake, hang on.
-Little buddy.
-Don't let go.
-What?
-Hey, what's Henry
Fonda doing there?
-Wherever there's a guy climbing
a mountain, he'll be there.
-Anybody want some coffee?
-Hey, strap work
crap to your belt.
-Yeah, I'll be all right.
-What's that?
-[INAUDIBLE]
-Uh-oh.
-Ah, grab the butt.
It makes a better handle.
-Hey, they're pantsing him.
-It's like bowling.
[LAUGHS] Ow, ouch.
-I'm fine.
I'm up already.
-Ow.
-Yup.
-Oh, this guy's a goner.
-I can smell it.
-He's dead.
-Dead for sure.
-Hey, watch out.
They're grabbing
kids' butts up there.
-Look, I'll thank you
not to touch my butt.
-Just-- just my hand
please, thank you.
-Uh-oh.
-Why do the violins
trill when he's climbing?
-Don't do it.
Don't you do it.
-I got nowhere else to go.
-Come on, Doc.
-Oh, please don't grab my butt.
I just had an operation,
if you don't mind.
-Just take my hand, OK?
-Well, who wants a drink?
-Whew.
-Give me a cigarette, will ya?
-The thinner the air,
the richer the smoke.
-Seems like we've been
climbing for days.
-Tell us about it.
-There's no top
to this rock pile.
-You got an
appointment somewhere?
-Ah, as a matter of fact--
-What's the matter, doc?
Anything wrong?
-No, just making a
check with the Geiger.
-Is that check current?
-Getting anything.
-Slight reading.
Very slight.
-From the rocket?
-No, from our heads, dickweed.
-Hey, John is your head clear?
-No, it's opaque.
-Sure.
-Wish I could say mine was.
-Mine's loose, I--
-Well, let's go.
-Well, it is.
-So soon?
-Go on, get your packs on.
-You got an
appointment someplace?
-Yeah, with a rocket.
-Call the rocket's secretary.
We'll have to reschedule.
-Here we go again.
-From the director
who brought you
that earlier stuff,
more of the same!
-Doesn't the action
let up for a moment?
-This is better than that
Indiana Jones truck sequence.
-Oh, that was the exciting
Odessa trip sequence.
-Not since Andy
Warhol's "Empire State"
has a camera stayed in
one place for so long.
[HUMMING]
-Oh, ugh.
[COUGHING]
-That can't be healthy.
Did somebody have a
Cobb salad or something?
Whew.
[COUGHING]
-I'm here, Steve.
-I warned you about
smoking that cigarette.
-Get up, you lizard.
-Come on.
Get up there.
Use your femur.
-What happened?
-He loved too much.
-It's poison gas.
-He who smelt it dealt it.
[LAUGHTER]
-Let it go.
We're here for you.
-Now I know what she meant
about her not coming back.
-Some kind of corrosive gas,
generated from the Earth.
-Yeah, yeah.
-Oh great, and me
with only a parachute.
I should have
brought a gas mask.
-Good one.
-Probably caused by
internal pressures.
-No, it was the Cobb salad.
I'm sure of it.
-There seems to be
considerable volcanic activity.
-Come on, can the
prune juice, Prof.
-You all right to go on?
-Yeah, sure.
-What's a little poison gas?
-Between friends.
-Got to find another way?
-Are you feeling
strong enough, Briggs?
-Perhaps you shouldn't continue.
-Oh, plot point.
Plot point.
-Yup.
Syd Fields would
put that earlier.
-Yup.
-Hey, what gives?
I don't know about that.
-Well, don't everybody
talk at once.
[THUNDER]
-They turned around and
the hitchhiker was gone!
-Hey, this is a no smoking cave.
-Anything to keep a
guy from sleeping.
-Since when did a little
noise keep you awake?
-Shut up, or I'll
short sheet your rock.
-Since a rocket
came into my life.
-Yeah, but look at all the
trouble it kept you out of.
-Ah.
-Duh.
-Ha, I love this
good-natured ribbing.
-Bob, uh, I'm on fire.
-Ah, this doesn't scare me.
I eat arachnids.
-Hm, I wonder if this
plot will ever get moving?
-Now, this is only
for conversation,
but if you were gonna
eat a human body,
where would you start?
-Hm.
-Can I snuggle with you guys?
[GIGGLING]
-You have family?
Came with the wallet.
-Yeah.
-The girl's 12.
The boy's 16.
-We're your family now.
-Fine looking kids.
-Name them after me, would you?
-We'll have quite a story to
tell them when we get back.
-Yes.
I hope I will.
-Hm.
-Hey, Hugh.
Where's the back of your skull?
-Well, that's what
I get for sitting
on my big, fat
blueprints and helping
to build guided missiles.
-Nice blueprints.
-This is actually pretty funny.
- --listen to my wife.
She's been after me for
years to get in condition.
[THUNDER]
-And God.
-I guess the natives
would say their--
their gods were angry tonight.
-I'd say they're bowling.
-And they're crazy.
-Ever been married, Major?
-You askin'?
-I've come close to it a couple
times, one way or another.
-How come you never
got pinned down?
-All done?
- --some wife tell him what
dames he should or shouldn't go
out with?
-Now say it without the
stick in your mouth.
[THUNDER]
-(GERMAN ACCENT) I
don't like the others.
I'll use their bones
to butter my bread.
-Kitty!
[LAUGHS]
-Up there, on the rock!
-You mean by that
gargantuan lizard?
-Art is art, but I
just don't see it.
-I'd say Doc's been sniffing
his polychlorinates again.
-Yeah, looks like Doc's been
writing his own prescriptions.
-(SLURRING) Eh, enough
of this for you.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
CROW (OFFSCREEN):
(WHISPERING) Music, music.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
CROW (OFFSCREEN):
(WHISPERING) OK, you've
got the [INAUDIBLE] camera.
You ready.
Everybody?
Shh. [CLEARS THROAT]
(ANNOUNCING VOICE)
"The Explorers," a
Quinn Martin production.
Starring Joel Robinson.
Also starring Crow
and Tom Servo.
With special guest
star, Michael Sarrazin.
Tonight's episode, "Drop
Personal Pronouns or Die."
Act I.
Oh, what I wouldn't give for a
charbroiled hamburger sandwich
and some french fried potatoes.
-Oh, you said it.
Mm-hm.
-Mm-hm.
-Greetings, naive native types.
I am Joel Robinson, explorer.
I come on great white
jet bird in sky.
-Oh, you mean that
DC-9 Stretch that
arrived at 1400 this morning?
-I come to teach you white way.
Teach you white man's tongue.
-Jeez, what is it with this guy?
-I show you great white culture.
Shakespeare-- be not
be that question.
Sinatra-- get no kick champagne.
Mere firewater no thrill.
Get kick you.
Kingston's-- Louie Louie,
oh baby, we got go.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
-You're high, aren't you?
-Act II.
-I come to--
-(WHISPERING) You're
primitive, backward people.
- --teach you people.
You know not about Bible.
You know not about, uh--
-(WHISPERING) Schools.
-Schools.
You know not about
Home Shopping Network.
-Servo, look at his eyes.
He's all tripped
up on goofballs.
-I here--
-Act III.
-I here to show
you ways of West.
Show you Judeo-Christian
way of life.
-Um, that's all
very well and good,
but why are you
talking like an idiot?
-(WHIPSPERING) Act IV.
-I need you guys
to talk this way,
because, uh, it's
the only way you
can help support the
white male reality.
-Oh, well, how do
you figure that?
-Well, as a white
man ravages his world
with his imperialistic
corporate sensibilities,
you see, you help support his
smug, superioristic attitude
by talking real dumb.
-Uh-huh.
-Jeez, this sketch
is getting preachy.
-OK.
Oh.
We make white devil feel good.
We talk like jerk.
-Great.
I knew I could count on you
simple backwards natives
to help me out.
-Glad we be of help.
Crow, kill him.
-Kill him!
Kill him!
-Epilogue.
-Kill him!
-I knew it, I knew it.
-So, thought you could
make Tom the fall guy,
didn't you, Tom Servo?
Pretty tricky.
But the truth is is you
killed Michael Sarrazin.
-What?
-You did it!
-Whoa, hey, what kind
of psychedelic voyage
are you on now?
-I don't know.
-He had it all figured.
He knew the perfect crime.
I even had Betty and
Jedediah check for prints,
but they came up short.
But you forgot the one thing
that every murderer forgets.
-Joel, Joel, Joel,
you're way off script.
What the hell are
you talking about?
-Uh, well, I-- I'm just
trying to find a way
to justify all this Quinn Martin
stuff with the Explorer stuff.
He never produced anything
with Explorer in it.
-OK, OK.
I did it.
I killed him.
And you know what?
I'm glad I did it!
Glad, I tell you, glad!
[EVIL LAUGHTER]
[ALARM]
[SHOUTING]
-What did you see up there?
-A monster I've
never seen before.
-And then what?
-I think he's
getting rocket happy.
-[CHUCKLES]
-Shut up.
You sure it wasn't
just your imagination?
-Uh, he has no imagination.
He's a scientist.
-I'm glad all I see is spots.
-We're going to
need a bigger cave.
We're going to get a
bigger cave, right?
Oh.
-So.
Wow, Phillipe, you're getting
a good draw off that thing.
[COUGH]
-It's very foggy.
-Mm-hm.
-Hey, the land of Dairy Queen.
-Ah, a whole new day
of rock climbing.
-Finally at the top, and
then I can get-- huh?
-Uh-oh.
-I don't think it's even close.
-Ugh.
-Careful, oh.
Hey, it's Edmund Hillary.
[COUGHING]
-Oh, whew.
-Hey you kids, get
down from there.
Break your neck.
-Or I'll break it for you.
-Oh, it looks like
what they're going
to do is keep the
camera on each actor
like a slow, painful
mantra of pain.
-Rock climbing, Servo.
-Rock climbing.
-Rock climbing, Crow.
Cambot, rock climbing.
-I hate when they put them
in the smoking section.
[GRUNTING]
-Hey, save the fog.
We could use it in
a Ridley Scott film.
-He just climbed
through the ionosphere.
Is that legal?
-Uh--
[GRUNTING]
-Oh, why don't you go on a diet?
Ah, ow.
-Oh, that's OK.
I didn't need that arm anyway.
Thank you.
-Well, we're finally
at the top-- oh.
-No.
-Come along, men.
Just a few more feet, and
we'll be a few more feet along.
-Oh, we're in hell.
Neat.
Hm.
-Hm.
-Neat.
-(ENGLISH ACCENT) Oh my
god, they've done it!
They've done it!
They've reached the-- side.
Huh?
-You know what I"m really
hungry for right now?
Rock lobster.
For some reason, I--
-Yeah.
-Anything by the B-52s, really.
-Robert Lippert presents "A
Mountain Out of a Molehill."
[HUMMING]
[SIGH]
[SNORING]
-Oh, come on!
What is this?
-What is it they're looking for?
-They forgot.
They don't even know.
-We could at least get
some music or something.
Stuff has to happen.
Come on.
-Come on!
God, why?
Why?
-This is a madhouse!
A madhouse! [CRIES]
-I never knew Mountain
Time was so slow.
-Please.
-Stay with me, baby.
-Come on, stay with me baby.
Is that all you can say? [CRIES]
-Kill them all!
Kill them!
Please, kill them!
-Come on.
Hey, you guys.
Calm down.
It's only a movie.
We can handle it.
OK?
-OK.
I guess you're right.
-Who are you?
Where are we?
-Can we get a frame of
reference or something?
Please!
-Joel, chill.
Joel, come on.
It's OK.
-Whew.
-It's only rock climbing.
-Would someone please
tell the director
about compressing
time through editing?
-Dun da dun da.
Oh, sorry.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
-Ah.
-Oh, there we go.
Oh, finally.
-Tense music.
-Come on, baby.
Do something.
-(GERMAN ACCENT) Should I
play out this plot point?
Oh, what the hell?
Forget Sig Field.
-Yeah.
-Got to try and keep
padding out the film.
Got to pad the film!
-Yes!
Oh, yes!
My spirit is snoring.
-Hm.
-Oh.
-That's a new sensation.
-Yeah.
That looks different.
New set.
-(GERMAN ACCENT) Got a match?
-Yeah, my butt your face.
[LAUGHTER]
-Woo!
Woo-hoo.
-Huh?
Oh, jeez.
This guy's going to bring the
film to a screeching halt now.
-(ECHOING) Rostov.
-Nolan, it's Briggs!
(ECHOING) Nolan, it's Briggs!
-How do they do that, do that?
That's really, neat neat.
-This film sucks, sucks.
-(GERMAN ACCENT) You
must die, my friend,
to make the film
more interesting.
-I'll never let go of you.
I will never, ever
let you fall or--
[SCREAMING]
-Oh, well.
-I'm all right.
I'm OK.
-I've plummeted to my
death, and I can't get up!
-Damn.
He has my keys.
-Hey, what happened, gramps?
You lose something?
-(GERMAN ACCENT) Yes, but the
light is so much better over
here.
-So what are they waiting for?
-The impact.
-Oh.
-How did it happen?
-I'm not sure.
I think it was his heart.
-He died of a broken heart?
-Why didn't you yell?
-There wasn't time.
-[INAUDIBLE] person.
-It was unexpected.
I tried to hold him, but I
didn't have the strength.
-(GERMAN ACCENT) I've
got no more love to give.
-Another one of
your unpredictables?
-(GERMAN ACCENT) Oh, I see.
I'm the jerk.
Everyone dump on me.
-Ya.
-(GERMAN ACCENT) Can't
you see I'm hurting?
Fade to black.
I hate--
-Well, that's over.
Let's go.
-No!
-No more rock climbing!
-Get your paws up that
mountain, you damn dirty apes!
-Why?
Can we go out and a
pizza or something?
-Just live with
the hurt, you guys.
Tough it out.
Get stronger.
-Sea shells.
How in the world?
-It used to be a lake.
-Oh.
-Dead end.
-All right, let's
go back, everybody.
-No, no, no.
-Hey, a whole other mountain,
and twice as big as this one.
-No, no, no.
-That's the only way up?
-Think you can make that?
-Oh, I don't know.
I'd have to heat my
core to 13,000 degrees,
get involved in
plate tectonics--
-Not the mountain, you idiot.
-Oh, make the jump.
I see.
-A long way down.
-Oh, it'll be quicker
than the way up.
-Mm, Noonan.
-Noonan.
-Noonan Noonan.
-Noonan, Noonan, Noonan.
-Miss!
-Oh.
-Jeez, you're like
a gazelle, Cesar.
-Now, throw me the whip!
-Throw me the item.
-Who is this, Robert
Mapplethorpe again?
-Whoa.
-Look, if you want to be in the
club, you've got to jump it.
-Don't trip.
-Whoa!
Hold me.
Dear God, hold me.
-I am free!
-It's a dead end over there.
-I am free.
-You've got to make this jump.
-Or you're not in the club.
-Well, this should
thin the cast a bit.
Leave more lines for us.
-We're swinging
into high now, Bill.
-Eh.
-They're on to of Old Smokey.
-[COUGH] You know, this
is secondhand smoke is--
is just as unhealthy.
-Hey guys, watch this.
I saw this on "Mannix" once.
-Don't trip.
-Ba dup ba dup.
-Thank you.
-Don't trip.
-Whoa!
-The Russian judge
gives him a 3.5.
-Hey guys, watch I saw
it on "Mannix" once.
-Ba dup ba dup.
-Noonan.
-Noonan, Noonan.
Ah.
Oh we got-- oh.
-Don't grab him
by the butt again.
-There he goes.
-You know, even the
rock climbing movies
don't have this
much rock climbing.
[COUGHING]
-Oh, Joel.
[COUGH] Kick his hand.
Step on him.
-(GERMAN ACCENT) I saw
this on "Mannix" once.
We prove the best athletes.
-We'll hit the top!
-Broadway!
-You mean the very top.
-Oh, we've got time to kill.
Let's take a break.
-Doug McClure?
What?
-Oh, this is great.
This is typically great.
There's an elevator right here?
We could have rowed up.
-Hey guys, there's
another mountain up here.
-No!
-Just kidding.
Just kidding.
Heh.
-Hey, this isn't so great.
20 minutes of climbing for this?
-Can we see what it is, please?
-Wow.
Would you guys look at all
this really cool stuff.
-Now I know how high is up.
-They really got
something going here.
It's too bad they won't show us.
-Look at that.
-What's the matter?
-Look.
-Oh, wow.
Cool stuff.
Well, let's get back
down the mountain.
-It's the jungle goddess sets.
-Hey.
-Trees, wow.
I've gone colorblind.
-Hm.
-Well, if this
movie were in color
that would mean something.
-I'm going slice off a
piece of that action.
-Look.
It's that girl and
the little kid again.
Oh, no.
We just went back
down the other side.
Doh.
-We're back at reel two.
Get word to the projectionist.
Get on reel four and get
us the hell out of here.
-Laundry everywhere.
Notions, assorted sundry
toiletries, everywhere.
-Well men, let's
bungle in the jungle.
-What do you make of it, Doc?
-I don't know.
-You can make a full-length
movie out of it.
-I'm almost afraid to say.
Not like any jungle
I've been in.
-Or ever will be, major.
-You're looking
at a kind of world
that hasn't existed
for millions of years.
-Who are you, Camus?
-Sort of like a--
like a lost continent.
-Ah, you could call
it that I guess.
-Hey, good name.
-Hm.
-Climb a mountain in
the middle of the sky.
-Heavy.
-Volcanic dust.
-Came out of my pant leg.
-It's almost as if
time forgot this place.
-Everything indicates a
throwback to prehistoric times.
Look at that foliage.
-You look at it.
I'm bitter.
- --tremendous internal
pressures causing such steamy
pools.
-I told you it was
the Cobb salad.
- --activity at such altitude.
-Must be terrific.
As powerful as a stockpile
of hydrogen bombs.
-Or a stockpile
of stock footage.
-Yeah, but it
doesn't make sense.
-The air is thin,
sure, but you can
breathe without your
lungs screaming for help.
-We're screaming for help.
-It's all the plants, Major.
Practically pure oxygen.
-But look at this haze.
-Purple haze.
-Somebody got lonesome
for some soft light,
put a green bulb in the sun.
-Yeah, like in a nightclub.
Only they forgot to
bring on the dames, huh?
-Thank you, Morty Gunty.
-We know what the atom bomb
did to the atmosphere, Major.
The same forces
could exist here.
-Uh, I think his accent has
gotten thinner with the air.
-If we find that rocket,
it may have us someday
all living back in a
world like this one.
-I'll worry about that
when the time comes.
-God know we've got tons
of that lying around.
-Hey Phillips, take a fix.
See if we can pick up a reading
on the rocket somewhere.
-Oh, the rocket.
Thank you.
I forgot what we were doing.
-Yeah.
-Well, that was when I was 14.
Now, later that summer, I--
-Tell me something, Joe.
What's eating you?
-Chili peppers.
I burned my gut.
-Privately, what is it?
Drop in this little dream world.
-Maybe.
-Maybe not.
-What do you think of Rostov?
-I like him.
He's neat.
-Rostov?
-I can light a
cigarette, maybe if I--
-He's a cold fish.
You know those big brains.
-No, can't say as I do.
-Oh.
I see.
You think that he--
-I don't think anything.
-Well, we know that.
-I never did buy that guy,
even before we took off.
-Well, the producer did.
-Do we know anything
about the rocket?
Willie?
No.
Only three guys know
what makes it work.
-And none of them
are in this film.
-Rostov, Phillips, and Briggs.
-What about Hunga Dunga?
-Oh, you left him out.
And he's the most
important one, too.
-Anything happens to Phillips,
that just leaves Rostov.
He could sell us
any bill of goods.
Maybe he didn't want
that rocket to turn back.
-Hm.
-Rough.
-See what you make of this.
-Oh, earmuffs I guess.
-Hey Major, we
picked something up.
-Well, let's hope it's a
virus and it kills them all.
-That's it, Phillips!
-What's the rundown?
-Definite signs
of radioactivity.
Much too powerful to be coming
from the unit in the rocket.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
-We may have hit something
important, Major.
-Like the plot?
-Uranium.
-Please say it's the plot.
I hope it's the plot.
-Explains a lot of things--
why the plane went out
of control when we
flew toward the island.
-Why domestic comedies
are so successful.
-We must have entered
a field of radiation.
And then we dropped below the
mountain, we passed out of it.
It lost its effect.
-Why couldn't you have told
us this 20 minutes ago, you?
-Does that stuff
act like a magnet?
-That stuff is the most
mysterious element in nature.
-Love?
-The most dangerous.
-(GERMAN ACCENT) It's potent.
-The most unstable,
the most valuable.
-Yeah, babies cry for it.
-Huh?
I think he lost you, Cesar.
-(GERMAN ACCENT) Keep
my uranium out of this.
- --ran out of fuel, it was
inevitably drawn to these
fields.
If
-It ran out of fuel
-Don't ever say that.
-Simmer down, Joe.
-So I'll apologize if I'm wrong.
-Meh.
-All right.
It's the only led we have.
Let's follow it.
-That square bugs me.
He really bugs me!
-Easy, easy.
-Rules of the road, boys.
See anything, shoot to kill.
I mean, don't shoot
it if it's going
to advance the plot, though.
-Saigon.
I can't believe I'm in Saigon.
-Did you get him, Sergeant?
-Oh please let him
get malaria, please.
- --for four hours like I was
something sent up from room
service.
-[RIMSHOT]
-This movie makes "Shoah"
look like a two-reeler.
-Easily.
-Think of any late news flashes
from the home front, Doc?
-Huh?
-How's everybody
at the Pentagon?
Happy?
-What did you say?
-Oh, nothing.
I just wondered--
-I just thought I'd
sneak a few lines in.
-Oh, well, from
this activity, we're
moving into a hotter zone.
-Well, at least we
won't freeze tonight.
-You coming on to me?
-And there are on
the handle was a--
-Well, if that rocket is
near the uranium fields,
we're getting pretty close.
I show a concentration
of almost 20,000 MRs.
-MRs?
-Like a handful of yurs?
-How about a short translate
for the common man, Doc?
-Go scratch.
Is that short enough?
-Billy who?
-It's like taking your
temperature, Sergeant.
-Yeah, now bend over.
-Only this shows how hot a
zone is with radioactivity.
-How dangerous is the area?
-Don't worry, Major.
We're safe enough.
But if the uranium in
those fields were refined,
we'd have been dead hours ago.
-The Japanese would have
owned all this anyway.
-Raise your flaps.
That rocket won't find us.
-You've been sarcastic
this whole film.
Is something wrong?
-I joined the Air Force.
-Oh, fun.
-Yeah.
[SARCASTIC LAUGHTER]
-Ah, let's take a
15-minute break.
-Oh, but keep the
camera running.
[GROANING]
-Break out the rations, Sarge.
-They take a lot of
breaks, those guys.
-Ah, tortellini
with pesto sauce.
-I've got radicchio.
-I've got haggis.
-This sauce is delicious.
It's so light.
Something tastes like
cilantro, only milder.
My compliments to Dinty Moore.
-Mm-hm.
-This is so good, I've
got to go tell someone.
-Hey.
Who booted over here?
[LAUGHTER]
-Hey, we've got company.
-All right.
Clean this place up.
We've got company.
-Yuck.
Ew.
-Carrots and stuff.
-What is that?
-These tracks are fresh.
-Mountain cows.
Nothing scarier.
-Fine, they're fresh.
But what do they fit?
-Nothing human eye ever saw.
Not even my top sergeant
had feet that big.
-Hm.
-I've seen tracks
like these before.
-Yeah, where?
-Larry Mondello.
-In a museum.
-[INAUDIBLE] Museum
in Citrusdal.
Rode one.
It almost bucked me
off, but I took him.
-Good for you.
-Hard to believe,
isn't it, Major?
-My calendar says 20th
century AD not 100 million BC.
-Yeah, but you've got
a Chippendale calendar.
-I appreciate your
feelings, Major,
but you can't change
what we've seen.
-I know, I know.
-Film.
-Come on.
Let's get our packs.
We've got to move.
-Oh, can I finish my yogurt?
It's really delicious.
It's got--
-Ah, now this is where
they shot "Mad Monster."
In a little ways
down here, you'll
see where they did
"Jungle Goddess."
There's "Rocket Ship XM,"
filmed right here too.
-Oh, neat.
-I'll make another
check if you like.
-Oh, that'll take 10 minutes.
-Oh.
-Would you put that
thing down, please?
-All right.
On course.
-Good.
-Yeah.
You sure that thing
really works, Hugh?
-Hey, Doc.
More bronto-- more tracks.
-Bronto Ham [INAUDIBLE]
-[INAUDIBLE] and the tracks
and the [INAUDIBLE] over.
-Hey, Doc.
Think there's some other way to
get those uranium fields, huh?
-Well, maybe.
-Well, yeah, we could have had
an edit about 25 minutes ago.
-OK.
-Ye lady whoa.
-So I'll just stay here right
with the thing and the-- cop?
Huh?
-Hey, Doc.
I think I'll stick with
the needle too, huh?
-Oh, Sid and Nancy are coming.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
-Hey, I saw a werewolf
drinking a pina colada
at Trader Vic's and
his hair was perfect.
-Hm.
-Here, plot.
[WHISTLING]
-Plot!
Here, plot.
Storyline!
Anywhere.
Hm?
-Hey, brontosaurus!
-Where?
-Hey!
All right.
-Yeah.
Woo!
Brontosaurus.
-I've been waiting for the last
50 minutes, but I've got to go.
They tell me a cost
over $1,000 a minute.
I'll have to see you later.
Now a word from Hunt Wesson.
-He brought
Stravinsky with them.
-It's magnificent!
-I ditched a hot babe for this?
-It turns out I'm a herbivore.
These guys got nothing
to worry about.
I'm really just a red herring.
Please enjoy the film.
And now word from
Jay's Potato Chips.
You'll enjoy it.
-Get the camera.
-A camera?
Doh.
-Ah, "canaps." "Hors
devores," don't mind if I do.
-Get away!
Brontosaurus in Africa?
-Sh.
-I win.
-Oh, get up, you.
-Get up the tree!
-Yeah, climb up to
mouth-level, real quick.
-Don't shoot Hugh.
[ROARING]
-Oh, my favorite,
scientist on a stick.
I like it when there's a salad
bar with a little meat on it.
[GUNSHOTS]
-Oh, oh, that stings.
Knock it off, will ya?
-I'm trying to knock it off.
[ROARING]
-I see a dinosaur, but
I hear an elephant.
Hm.
-Shoot me, will ya, smart boy?
You're not gonna forget
this, you can bet.
-Get him out of here!
-He's going to look
good over the fireplace.
-Mm-hm.
-Get out of here.
-One more.
There you go.
-Now throw the gun.
Oh.
-15 minute-- no, that
was pretty intense.
Let's go for 20 minutes.
[SIGHING]
-It's up on that rock.
-More rocks?
No!
[GROANING]
-No, not more rocks.
There they are, too.
Even the small ones are going
to take a lot of time guys.
[GROANING]
-Sorry I had to tie
you guys up, but you
were letting the film get away.
-Just keep your nylon
all in one piece, baby.
I may be needing you yet.
-Still talking to
crap, huh, monkey boy?
-Hm.
-Throw that thing
over the side, please.
-Pictures?
-You're lucky you
weren't killed.
-Uh, that's the thing.
I was killed.
We're all in hell now.
-How do you account
for all this, Doc?
How do you explain it?
-Oh, it's just the
way Lippert works.
He's kind of a kook.
-It's an impossibility.
Yet here we are, right
in the middle of it.
-Hm.
-It's where I always wind up.
-Stuck in the middle with you.
-That animal we
saw this afternoon
hasn't existed for millions
and millions of years.
-But it almost chomped
your butt, Hugh.
-It disappeared before
man was ever heard of.
-What's the matter with it?
-Shut up, you two.
And don't spill the beans.
We've got a good 20
minutes left to fill.
-You know what a
miracle is, Lieutenant?
-The words "the end."
-Amen.
-Can you explain it?
-No.
I can't explain what happened
this afternoon, either.
-Candy.
-Oh, thanks for straightening
the whole thing out, Doc.
You took the words
right out of my mouth.
Ha, and what a relief.
Oh, good night.
-Jeez, just close me out.
-I'll call you when
it's your watch.
-A watch?
For 50 years of movie service?
[ROARING]
-Oh, very impressive.
-Sorry.
-Strange and rather
frightening out there.
-And strange.
-Take any of those rocks--
-Please.
-Harness its stored up energy.
-Mm-hm.
-Convert it into power plants.
-We can build a whole new world.
-Oh, somebody's got a
secret agenda, I guess.
Destroy the one we've got.
-Ironic, but here we are
sleeping on top of the richest
uranium--
-Moronic?
- --field known to man.
-Yeah, it's not like
your futon back home.
-It's s real cozy feeling.
-One day I'll be able to still
my three-headed grandchildren.
-You are a cynical, suspicious
man, aren't you, Nolan?
-No I'm not.
Who told you that?
-Maybe.
-Maybe not, dickweed.
-No, no.
Danny, Danny, not the
clown suit, Danny.
No.
-And your shape.
-Huh?
-Uh-huh.
-Perfect.
-Yeah.
-Hey, I don't feel like I
should be watching this.
-Me neither.
-Yeah, where's that
copy "Aviation Weekly"?
-Turn to the Cessna-- woo.
-There's just one
thing about you, baby.
-Oh, what's that?
-If you could just--
if you could just have
propellers instead of jets.
-Wa, wa, wa, wa.
-I feel so dirty after that.
Football practice!
-Oh, phew.
-[INAUDIBLE]
mountain [INAUDIBLE].
-Hey, does this movie have
a continental breakfast?
-Uh, no.
No.
They, uh lost the
continental breakfast.
[LAUGHTER]
-Oh, this was also called
"Cesar Romero's Night
of the Living Dead."
-Rostov and Phillips,
they're gone.
-Huh?
-Oh, they went to
Perkin's without us.
-Hey, you were on guard,
why didn't you watch them?
-Well, you know
how unstable I am.
-I did.
I never closed my
eyes all night.
-Maybe Alex is right.
-I knew it.
-Everyone, Ronnie, Biff,
get all the tea titans.
Let's move like we
never moved before.
-When stools ruled the world.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
-Got to find where that
music is coming from!
-Huh, maybe if we
go around here,
we'll be on the other
side of the same thing.
It's kind of funny over here.
-Oh, what he stepped in.
-It came out of a
dinosaur, I'm sure.
-Who brought the string bass?
-It's a contrabasso, sir.
-Shut up, maggot.
-Hey, look.
The cast of "Star Trek."
-Help me, Spock.
Help me, Spock.
-Hey, cool it.
I see something interesting.
-Oh.
Shoot 'em.
-They're loving.
-I'm repulsed. [GAG]
-Some rouge here, add
a little foundation.
You look just-- huh.
-What are you doing?
-Oh, I'm just
applying some makeup.
-He became lodged in the rocks.
I wasn't able to
free him by myself.
-So I chewed his leg off.
-Keep your voices down.
Look.
-Hi, I'm Skippy.
Don't be afraid
of me or anything.
-He's been hanging
around for hours,
ever since I discovered
Dr. Phillips.
-He's only reading
the magazines.
I don't think he's
going to buy anything.
-Mm, nummy, nummy, nummy, nummy.
-Come on, I just want to talk.
Come back!
-Well, it's no good.
Noise will only attract them.
We'll have to sweat it out.
-Get up, Steve.
Come on.
Get to work, you pansy.
-He must be dreaming
about a plane.
-No, June!
Not the clown suit.
Oh.
-Go ahead and yell.
Do you good.
You got us trapped into this.
Now go ahead and yell loud.
[YELLING]
-He was being sarcastic.
-Oh.
-What's a few more
lives, you crazy, stupid,
uranium-happy-- Hey, don't
talk to my friends that way.
-Shoot for the eyes.
-Uh-oh.
-Where have you been?
I've been looking
for you all day.
[ROAR]
-It's the mother-loving
rubber dinosaur of them all.
-You go around back,
I'll take the front.
yeah.
-I am not an animal.
I am a rubber model.
-I wonder how he keeps
his hair back like that.
He kind of looks
like Patti LaBelle.
-You and me, going round
and round, model a model.
-Hurts, don't it?
Here's your mail.
Oops, forgot to stamp it.
-Sergeant, keep your eye on him.
-Start plotting those spitballs.
-Yeah.
-Gee, Dad, why'd you have to
get a green-stick fracture.
-I'm eating you up now.
Heh, how's the farm?
Here's a couple more acres.
-You got him.
[SCREECHING]
-Just as dinosaurs must
protect their young,
so must you invest
in Mutual of Omaha.
-Help Danny get him out.
-Eat it, boy.
Eat it.
Arr.
-Oh, oh, ow.
You got my braces.
Ow, owie.
-They're gone.
We can quit now.
Let's go.
-Say uncle.
-Dinasure.
-Aw, but this is
the coolest part.
-Help me, I'm about to fall.
You've got to help me!
I'm pulling my arm
out of the socket.
Don't grab by butt.
Ah!
TOM (OFFSCREEN): Hey, Joel.
Come over here and look at this.
CROW (OFFSCREEN): Yeah,
this is really cool.
-Hey, Cambot.
Follow me over here.
CROW (OFFSCREEN): Wow, yeah.
-Wow, that thing's super neat.
-Cool, huh?
-Oh, just wait a minute.
Wait.
It's coming around.
There.
-Whoa.
-Oh, man.
-Oh, boy.
Oh, boy.
I think that's the coolest part.
-Well, the other side
was really cool too.
-Yeah, it sure was.
-Oh, wow.
Those little dangly things
at the top are the coolest.
-I don't know.
I don't know.
I think-- come on, look
at the top half there.
Top half near the sides.
That's the coolest part.
-I don't see it.
-Well, maybe.
I don't know.
Hey, wouldn't two of
them be even cooler?
-No way.
Nuh-uh.
-But 18 of them, whoa-ho, wow.
-That would be really cool.
-That would be great.
-Boy oh boy.
-Like you could-- yeah.
Hey, guys, look at that.
-What?
-Wait for it to come around.
OK.
Now!
-Wow!
-Oh man, that's so cool.
-That's real deece.
-Unbelievable.
Oh, now it knows it's cool.
It's not that cool anymore.
Let's get out of here.
-Yeah, I'm coming down now.
It was pretty cool while it
lasted though, wasn't it?
-I still think it's pretty cool.
You know.
It was not as cool as
before, but-- hey, guys.
Hey, hey, guys!
Look!
-What, what what?
-Look.
-Oh, wow.
Oh, cool.
-Baby, that's the coolest.
-Yeah.
-Hey, Joel, it's cool
and all, but what is it?
-Uh, it's--
-Well, at least
we know it's cool.
-Hey, do you know what it is?
-If you think you do, send
your description, drawing,
orthographic projection,
or expensive working model
to Cool Thing, care of MST 3000
Information Club, post office
box 5325, Hopkins
Minnesota, 55343.
-What do you think, sirs?
Pretty cool, huh?
-I don't think it's cool.
I think it's subterfuge.
I think you're just trying
to hide the fact that we're
winning and you're losing.
Put the movie back in, Frank.
-It's so simple, yet
so beautiful in a way.
There's a kind of arcane
beauty, you know. [WHEEZING]
-We need to talk.
Go away.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
-Meanwhile, in a less
interesting part of the film.
-Man was that ever
action-packed.
We better take a
15 minute break.
-All you scientists lose your
marbles every now and then.
-I never lose my marbles.
I'm a scientist.
-I'm sorry to have caused you
so much trouble, Lieutenant.
I woke up a little earlier
than the rest of this morning.
seemed a swell chance
to grab some pictures.
-I'm a morning person,
what can I say?
ROSTOV (OFFSCREEN):
Think I'd let
you get yourself killed
in a prehistoric jungle?
We've been friends too long.
-(GERMAN ACCENT) I
love you, damn it.
-Well, the, uh, the
leg's feeling better.
Come on, let's
keep walking, huh?
-My god, he's cheerful.
It's hard to get mad at him.
-Mm-hm.
-[HUMS] Thunk.
Oh, my head. [HUMS] Thunk.
Oh, my head.
-Oh, check it out.
Graffiti from the Donner party.
Hm.
-(GERMAN ACCENT)
Candy cigarette?
They're toasted.
-Thanks.
-I think.
-You're not disturbed because
it's still BC instead of AD?
-No, because I'm
AC and you're DC.
-CD?
-C.
-ASAP.
-It's smoother.
I'm energized.
-I also said if I was
wrong, I'd apologize.
-That's not necessary.
-OK, enough of that, then.
-Don't ask me why,
but at the beginning,
I had you figured for
playing on the wrong team.
-Hm.
-I know.
I'm a Russian.
-I thought you were German.
-Almost my whole life has been a
witch hunt, one way or another.
-Did you ever get a
wedgie in grade school?
- -- Hitler and one of
his concentration camps.
-Hitler, what a jerk.
-And then my wife
and unborn child
died in another, with
Russian-made barbed wire.
It doesn't change them much.
-A lot of guys are finding
that out every day.
-All respect for my country
lies dead in those camps.
-I guess I should like you now.
-I hope to go back and
resurrect it some day.
-Mm-hm.
-Hm.
-No country can
survive when it loses
the respect of its own
people or of the world.
-Oh, it hasn't stopped
the old US of A.
-You go back, Mike, the
way you want to go back.
-My god, your hat smells good.
- --fighting for the
same thing, even if--
-Uh, line?
- --heave forbid, it means
pushing buttons on more rockets
like the one out
there somewhere.
-Blowing up the world.
-Heaven forbid, Joe.
-What did you call me?
-Let's go home.
-You take that Walkman off.
You're closing out the world.
- --coming up the mountain,
being forced through the earth
at tremendous pressures.
-(GERMAN ACCENT) I
know what that is.
-Too much pressure
with no safety valve.
-That's colitis, all right.
-If it should ever react
with the uranium fields--
-Like the fourth of July.
-Or the end of the world.
-Oh, that's it.
-That's what?
-A whole lot of batteries.
-It's the end of the road.
The Geiger can't
take us any further.
-He means that we are right
in the middle of the uranium
deposits and they
seem to explain why.
-I know what it means.
Shut up.
-Then how do we find the rocket?
-I wish I knew.
It could be anyplace.
-You mean we can wander
around up here for weeks?
Come on.
Let's get out of this graveyard.
-Yeah.
-Let's blow.
I hate this place.
-I agree, let's go.
-This stinks.
-Well, and here we are again.
Look, even Cesar's
sick of it by now.
-I don't know how long
these guys will hold out.
They've got pleats in
their pants, [INAUDIBLE].
-What's eating you?
-Making this movie is
probably the worst three days
of my life, that's what.
-We're beating our brains up
for something we may never find.
We don't even know
where to look now.
If the rocket's
up here, it'll rot
before anybody can get to it.
-You bored?
-Yes, I'm bored.
Let's do something.
-Yeah, I'm bored.
We're down to our last
few rounds of ammo.
Worried?
No.
-Scared?
A little.
-Aroused?
You bet.
-If I see more of those
fugitives from the zoo,
I'll just walk up to them
and kill them with spit.
-Oh, it just might work.
You haven't brushed
since we got here.
-Hey, this is fun.
I'm having fun.
How about you guys?
Yeah.
Neat.
-Are you speaking for
yourself, Danny, or for them.
-Maybe I'm saying what
they don't want to say.
-What are you saying?
I don't understand any of this.
-Lieutenant seems
to think you've
go something on your minds.
-Water on the brain.
[LAUGHS] Tease.
-I'll give you a chance
to unburden yourselves.
-(GERMAN ACCENT) Yeah, I
was forced to wear clown
suit as a youngster, and-- oh.
-Nothing to say?
-Well, I have.
[RASPBERRY]
-We're low on food.
We're low on water.
And we're low on ammunition.
-All we got are
those little silver
balls that go on tops of cakes.
-But I got news for you.
-OK.
-I walk around with my guts
twisted up, same as you.
-Well, take some Maalox.
-I want to clear out of
here the same as you.
I didn't ask to be
trapped in this rat race.
But as long as I'm here,
I'll try and finish.
-Same as you.
-Hm.
-Anybody who wants to
can knock it off now.
[APPLAUSE]
-Fell better, Major?
-Creep.
-Well, don't just
stand there, Major.
We've got a rocket to find.
-Jerk.
-Baby, you ain't
getting any lighter.
Wiener
-Uh-huh.
-So I'll spit in their eyes.
-Just a little spittle.
Idiot.
-Everybody's got a line but me.
[HUMMING]
-Uh, line, anybody?
Anybody?
-So, here we are again.
-Oh, no.
-Yup.
-Oh, yeah.
-Mm-hm.
Yup.
-Ay yai yai.
-Well, uh, this is where
we slept last night.
I remember this.
-Mm-hm.
-So--
[SCREECHING]
-Hey, it's a trumpeter swan.
-No.
-I'm Batman.
-You ain't free.
Wait till you get a load of me.
-Hey, I wonder if a
piece of that big buzzer
would make good eating.
-Hey, shouldn't he be
on the Pee-wee set?
[GUNSHOTS]
-Hey!
-Hey, somebody shot Terry!
-Nice job, uh.
[BARKING]
-Where is it, boy?
Soft mouth it.
-Oh, we'll get some sage
stuffing and some cranberries.
-Hey, look?
-Huh?
-Hey, there it is!
-Oh, with a mad
passion, I love you.
-Let's get to it.
-Mwah.
-Hey likes all those things.
-Mm-hm.
-Uh, you won't be
happy when you find out
what you're leaning in.
-Take it easy with
that, you big slob.
-Hey.
Hey, who are you talk-- oh,
you're talking to the dinosaur.
-Hm, brain the size of a walnut.
-Dinosaurs?
-No, the director.
-Oh.
-Mm-hm.
-They should drop dead.
-They should've a few
million years ago.
-Well, we can't wait
for them become extinct.
-Hey, Rostov.
How much time will you need to
get the unit out of the rocket?
-Well, that's kind of personal.
-Depends on how
much damage we find.
Ordinarily, 10, maybe
15 minutes might do it.
-Another five to get the
data off the lab recording
instruments.
-Ten years.
-Can you knock off whole
works in half an hour.
ROSTOV (OFFSCREEN): Should
give us plenty of time.
-OK.
15 minute break, everybody.
-It's gonna be rough.
But it might work.
-Danny, you and Willie
circle the animals.
-Mm-hm.
-Get in back of the rocks and
boulders and start shooting.
-Yeah.
-Roger.
-It might bait them away
from the rocket long enough
for Rostov and
Phillips to move in.
-OK.
-Gotcha.
Now get this.
-We're going to shoot
the works on this.
-Mm-hm.
Mm-hm.
-We don't do it the
first time, we've had it.
-Right Mm-hm.
-Hope you got plenty of spit.
We might run out.
[HOCKING]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
-Hey, so I'll meet you
guys at the rocket.
-Hm?
[ROARING]
-What the hell is he doing?
-I'll make a sling
with my underwear.
-Hey, what did he call me?
-Now!
-Whoa.
-Hit a lot of pheasant that way.
-Let's get out of here, Scooby!
-Here, take this.
It's chafing me like a bear.
-Take it in a little.
Quick, get the can opener.
-Oh, yeah.
-Fisher.
-Hey, kegger at the rocket!
Woo!
-All right.
Party down.
-Hey, yeah.
It's really deep.
-Oh.
-Watch out for that last step.
It's a doozy.
-I'll just stand
here, tall and proud,
keeping Amer-- well, South
America, Latin America
safe for democracy.
-Looking good, boss.
You're really looking
tall and proud.
Wow, there's tons of
cool stuff down there.
OK.
-Hey, we found a party ball.
-Woo!
-All right!
-Ah, finally.
My light brown pumps
from Bloomingdale's.
-Hm, let me take looks at this.
-Strap those on and parade
around singing show tunes.
-They're fabulous.
-Mm-hm.
-Do 'em.
Let's do 'em.
-You will die at the
hands of a triceratops?
-Maximum thrust registered 9.5.
-And I designed the
controls for 2.5.
A team of those
animals out there
couldn't have turned it back.
-What does that mean?
-It means a team of those
animals out there-- oh.
-Eminently, Major.
-Now that we have
these, we'll know
how to design the next one.
-Good.
-No more unpredictables.
-That's good.
-Hey, remember when
you took that pot
shot at me, monkey boy?
Payback time.
-Well, everything's going good.
-I feel like a little Italian.
-Huh?
-My little pizza roll, ha, ha.
[GUNSHOTS]
-Tell the plane I love her!
[SLURPING]
-Hey, cut it out.
I'm eating. [BELCH]
-Hey, come on.
Ow.
Bunch of jerks. [BELCH]
-Huh?
-Wow.
-Take it slow and
easy on the way down.
-That was a short
mourning period.
-Yeah.
-I don't want to lose anymore.
-What about their friend?
Oh, no.
Guys, now it's the trip down!
[CRYING]
-I can't take it.
I can't take it.
Oh.
-[SNIFFS] I remember
when I pulled monkey
boy up over the cliff here.
[CRYING]
-You know, this is
going a lot faster now.
-Oh, on the way down?
It usually does.
-OK, carefully.
Now watch your step there.
No, you want to be real
careful on the way down.
Don't want to break an ankle
or cause some kinda-- oh.
Oh.
That hurt.
-Please, don't
spare us anything.
Let's watch Hugh
go through it too.
-Whoa!
-As slow as possible.
-Whoa, that wasn't very smart.
-Give him a hand.
He's hung up here.
-I'm not always
going to be here.
Don't grab his butt, Joel.
-You know, guys if
you ask me, I think
they just reversed
the film here.
Yup.
Going backwards here.
-Hm.
-Twinkie wrappers.
We were here before.
-Yup.
-I'm going to ask
this once again,
and it's only for the
sake of conversation,
but what do you think
is the tastiest part
of the human body?
Hands?
-How's the leg holding up?
-Nose?
-I'll make it.
You, Mike?
-See, one, two.
Hey, there's a lot less of us.
No wonder it's going so well.
-Sure, he'd probably say--
[YELLING]
-Hey, it's gonna rain.
Let me go with that umbrella.
How do you like that?
-No, thank you, Joey Bishop.
-Uh-oh.
-We have to move fast.
-The whole mountain's
blowing up under us.
-Yup.
The model doesn't
look to do either.
-Where are they again?
-They're on top of that
pile of mashed potatoes?
-The souffle is falling.
-Well, grab a rock
and slide it down.
-Whoa!
Ow!
Oh, this is getting serious.
It's so real!
-Well, I'd say the
dinosaurs are rocking down.
-Whoa!
-What?
-The dinosaurs are rocking down.
Yup.
Oh, watch out.
-Oh!
-Whew, that was close.
-That was his ear.
-Oh, ho.
-Owie.
-That had to sting.
-Whoa.
Careful there.
-Step carefully.
-Oh, ouch.
-Hey, you kids, stop
jumping around out there.
Eddie, Lumpy, knock it off.
-Come on.
-That's nice when
there's no stones.
-Yeah, I like--
-Whoa!
-They've come to bury
Cesar, not to praise him.
-Oh, boy.
-Ha, ha.
-Rock the casbah.
-Uh-huh.
-It doesn't bug me anymore.
I'm used to it.
-I'm unaffected.
-That wasn't so bad.
-Nope.
-Let's get the hell out of here.
-You know, fellas, it doesn't
get any better than this.
We got to do this
again sometime.
-Guys, guys.
You're OK.
It's only the camera
that's shaking.
Come on.
-I got to get the girls
together and do this sometime.
-Yup.
-Well, let's take
a 15-minute break.
[LAUGHS] Uh, just kidding.
-How is it that those
rocks keep missing them.
It's, like, incredible.
-I don't know.
-It's like the Book
of Revelations.
But nothing-- but
nothing touches them.
-Must have been filmed in
Katherine Hepburn vision.
[LAUGHS]
-Uh-oh.
-Think you can jump that, Cesar?
-This is the wrong time of
year to visit San Francisco.
[ROARING]
-It's like Shake-a Pudd'n.
-Just shaking the bushes, boss.
-Whoa, whoa.
-Oh, how fortunate.
This will simplify everything.
-Throw me the whip,
I'll throw you the idol.
-Come on!
-I can't throw you the whip.
It's-- uh, never mind.
-You know, I can't be there
for you every time, dummy.
Come on.
Com on.
This is last time.
Quit horsing around.
-Get over here,
you lovable dork.
-Feel like a--
-Little buddy!
-Well, they must all
be out in the lagoon.
-Whoa.
Ho, ho.
-Look at that.
Cool.
-Oh, I bet the professor
rigged that, huh?
-Yup.
Oh.
-Hey, we can hide in
that shelter there.
-Well, it's kind of like
helter shelter right now.
-Oh, yeah.
-Hey, didn't they come by plane?
-Yeah.
-So they're gonna
steal a boat, huh?
-I'm telling you guys,
property values are great here.
It's a buyers' market.
-Yup.
-Look at this duplex you
could get for-- well,
it's going fast.
-Hey, their lean-to
just leaned fro.
-It's the end of the world as
they know it, and I feel fine.
-(SINGING) Yummy, yummy.
A dig, a dig bowlful.
Hm.
You get a big, big flavor.
-(SINGING) Oceans
of [INAUDIBLE].
Black Attila.
-Yup.
-Just in Java.
-Certainly not Pettonville.
-Get away, the stock
footage is erupting!
-Midway in sense surround.
-Senseless.
-December 7, 1941, a day
that will live in infamy.
-I'd like to go through that.
There it goes.
Looks like [INAUDIBLE].
-Oh, safe.
Out of danger.
-The world is coming to the end.
Shark!
-Ah!
-Shark!
ROSTOV (OFFSCREEN):
Better this way
than to have it go
on living with us.
-Well, smoke 'em if
you got 'em, boys.
-Let's go guys.
Let's go back.
-What do you think they'll
call the sequel, guys?
-Oh, "Padding and Paddling."
-That was the 1951
classic, "Lost Continent."
Interestingly enough,
EP Robert Lippert
found that he could extend
the length of his film
by adding meaningless,
poorly contrived,
and blocked walking sequences.
Or in the case of today's
film, mind-numbingly excessive
mountain climbing scenes.
He called the device padding.
And as you know, padding has
become a staple of movies
ever since.
Now this.
-Cesar Romero, whom many of you
will recognize from the Batman
TV series of the late '60s and
who was thought to be a spy,
was originally to
play the role that
eventually went
to Hugh Beaumont.
Director Sam Newfield said
Cesar just isn't bland enough.
We'll be right back.
-Uh, Director Newfield, a
known Nazi spy, cocaine fiend,
and pyromaniac, used to
amuse the cast and crew
by doing terrible things
to his dog with a fork.
Eh-- oh, we'll be right back.
-Anyway, I think we
got a letter to read.
I'd like to thank the Mads for
faxing these color letters up.
-Hey.
-Let's put this on the, uh, on
the still store there, Cambot.
I'll read it.
This is from Robby Harmon.
CROW (OFFSCREEN): Hey, Robby.
JOEL (OFFSCREEN): It says,
"Dear Mr. Joel, Crow, and Tom.
I am 10 years old.
I try to watch your
show all the time.
Your show is the best.
I like the sound effects
and the jokes you say.
They make me laugh so hard.
-Oh, good.
JOEL (OFFSCREEN):
"Sincerely, Robbie.
I drew your pictures."
That one kind of looks--
looks like you're
getting kind of
heavy there, Crow.
TOM (OFFSCREEN): It's
a chunky crow there.
-Yeah, that's me
before I Slim Fast.
-Anyway, uh, what do you
think of the experiment, sir?
-I think you guys should
get a special trip
treat for making it
through that film.
-I think you guys should
get a special little treat.
Frank, this is science,
not romper room.
-Oh, OK.
In that case, you
are going to die.
-Frank, listen to me.
I think.
-I think.
-We won.
-Push the button.
-[SIGH] God opens a
door, He closes a window.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
-Oh, thanks for straightening
the whole thing out, Doc.
You took the words
right out of my mouth.
[LAUGH]S And what a relief.
Oh, good night.